<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Terri's Adventures on the Rails]]></title>
  <link href="http://TLnielsen21.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://TLnielsen21.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-18T07:14:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://TLnielsen21.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Terri Lee Nielsen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[my first blog post]]></title>
    <link href="http://TLnielsen21.github.io/blog/2013/07/15/my-first-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-15T21:11:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://TLnielsen21.github.io/blog/2013/07/15/my-first-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Terri Lee Nielsen,  Davinci Coders</p>

<p>Jason Noble, Instructor-Building the Ruby Tool Belt</p>

<p>July 15,  2013</p>

<p>My professional background :</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Entrepreneurial project management in real estate, and medical device sales – 17
years</p></li>
<li><p> K-16 education – I hold a K-12 Principal license, &amp; K-12 Special Ed Director license, specialties in Literacy &amp; STEM for Gifted Learners, English Lang. Acquisition – ELL students, &amp; School Psychology – Gifted, Autism, .. + similar</p></li>
</ol>


<p>During my first few days as a &ldquo;Davinci Coder,&rdquo;&hellip; I&rsquo;ve focused on researching Electronic Health Records-EHRs &ndash; One of my reasons for learning to code.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Though I recently sold my “Co-founding Board Member” financial interest in a Medical Sales company,  I hope to continue my ties to the Med field.</p></li>
<li><p>Several physicians &amp; hospital organizations feel overwhelmed about the plethora of components involved with initiating and maintaining effective EHRs.</p></li>
</ol>


<p> Here&rsquo;s the email I sent to Boston Children&rsquo;s Hospital today :</p>

<p>Dr. Kohane, I see that you&rsquo;ve considered EHR software extensively for electronic health records. After reading some ins and outs of Epic and Cerner EHR software &mdash; I came across info about smaller Oroville Hospital, 3 hours north of San Francisco. Their CEO was hopeful that he&rsquo;d be able to use &ldquo;Open Source&rdquo; options &mdash; and upon connecting by phone with his exec asst &mdash; she said Robert Wentz is not disappointed in this tactic, to date. Seemed to me, that they were ~ 1.5 years into implementation. <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/08/24/open-source-electronic-health-records-a-cost-solution-for-hospitals/">http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/08/24/open-source-electronic-health-records-a-cost-solution-for-hospitals/</a></p>

<p>I read about you, Dr. Kohane, in a Forbes article on EHR topics &mdash; and wondered about your thoughts. I&rsquo;m an educational psychologist / + have K-12 School Principal &amp; Special Educ Director licenses. I&rsquo;m taking my first computer-programming course &mdash; and hope to explore this topic within an &ldquo;end of course&rdquo; project. Please share your thoughts.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m reading HIMSS.org standards – mainly looking for info about the stages that they articulate regarding Electronic Health Records &ndash; EHRs implementation.  I noticed from Forbes articles that some software owners took the position that their companies would earn a bundle &mdash;versus supporting doctors &amp; hospitals in full-scale transition to EHRs for lower costs, greater accessibilities, and “Free Source” resources.</p>

<p>I hope companies from this industry are transitioning their tactics.  I appreciate your thoughts.</p>

<pre><code>Thank you,       Terri Lee Nielsen,        Golden, Colorado


 Kohane &amp; Mandel's beliefs :          http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMp0900411


 Update on EHR field,Kohane &amp; M :     http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMp1203102
</code></pre>

<p>**  This link describes some of the staggering EHR implementation costs :</p>

<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/06/18/the-staggering-cost-of-an-epic-electronic-health-record-might-not-be-worth-it/">http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/06/18/the-staggering-cost-of-an-epic-electronic-health-record-might-not-be-worth-it/</a></p>

<p>** This link talks about a hospital CEO in California, who believed he could implement “Open Source.”   So far, 1 + year into the process, he is glad he took this route :</p>

<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/08/24/open-source-electronic-health-records-a-cost-solution-for-hospitals/">http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/08/24/open-source-electronic-health-records-a-cost-solution-for-hospitals/</a>   Robert Wentz, Oroville Hospital  – Northern California Hospital,</p>

<p>I am passionate about learning the Ruby Coding Language, within the EHRs medical context.</p>

<p>I hope that you will want to check-in with my posts along my way to Building the Ruby Tool-Belt ….!</p>

<p>Terri Lee Nielsen             Golden, Colorado</p>

<p>Davinci Coders         Davinci Institute            Boulder, Colorado</p>

<p>**</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
