<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Terri's Adventures on the Rails]]></title>
  <link href="http://TLnielsen21.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://TLnielsen21.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-17T23:41:44-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://TLnielsen21.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Terri Lee Nielsen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[my first blog post]]></title>
    <link href="http://TLnielsen21.github.io/blog/2013/07/15/my-first-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-15T21:11:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://TLnielsen21.github.io/blog/2013/07/15/my-first-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Terri Lee Nielsen,     Davinci Coders</p>

<p>Jason Noble, Instructor  &ndash; Building the Ruby Toolbelt</p>

<p>July 17,  2013</p>

<p>It’s nice to open my first github blog….!</p>

<p>My past professional work, and passions have involved :</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Entrepreneurial project management in real estate, and medical device sales – 17
years</p></li>
<li><p> K-16 education – I hold a K-12 Principal license, &amp; K-12 Special Ed Director license, specialties in Literacy &amp; STEM for Gifted Learners, English Lang. Acquisition – ELL students, &amp; School Psychology – Gifted, Autism, .. + similar</p></li>
</ol>


<p>First Day of Ruby Programming Class &ndash;  7 – 15 – 2013 –</p>

<p>I’m spending as many spare minutes as I can carve out, researching my “aggregate reason for wanting to learn to code.”</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Though I recently sold my “Co-founding Board Member” financial interest in a Medical Sales company,  I hope to continue working in the Medical field as part of a consultative team helping a hospital or physician practice successfully transition to use of EMRs, EHRs – Electronic Medical Records / Electronic Health Records.</p></li>
<li><p>The physicians / hospital group that I hope to open a working relationship doing this – feel overwhelmed about all that is involved.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>**  This link describes some of the staggering costs :</p>

<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/06/18/the-staggering-cost-of-an-epic-electronic-health-record-might-not-be-worth-it/">http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/06/18/the-staggering-cost-of-an-epic-electronic-health-record-might-not-be-worth-it/</a></p>

<p>** This link talks about a hospital CEO in California, who believed he could implement “Free Source.”   So far, 1 + year into the process, he does not regret passing up consultants &amp; sales</p>

<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/08/24/open-source-electronic-health-records-a-cost-solution-for-hospitals/">http://www.forbes.com/sites/zinamoukheiber/2012/08/24/open-source-electronic-health-records-a-cost-solution-for-hospitals/</a>   Robert Wentz, Oroville Hospital  – Northern California Hospital,</p>

<p>With this Building the Ruby Tool-Belt course, I have a burning desire to learn the Ruby Coding Language, within the EHRs medical context.</p>

<p>I’m diving into Chris Pine’s key concepts outlined in Learn to Program, 2nd Ed.</p>

<p>I hope that you will want to check-in with my posts along my way to Building the Ruby Tool-Belt ….!</p>

<p>Terri Lee Nielsen             Golden, Colorado</p>

<p>Davinci Coders         Davinci Institute            Boulder, Colorado</p>

<p>**</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
